<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Carson Slater&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://carsonslater.com/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://carsonslater.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Carson Slater&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://carsonslater.com/media/icon_hu0d1b359ff755bc8a5277e5449e3824a5_220651_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Carson Slater&#39;s Blog</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further event details, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page elements&lt;/a&gt; such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quite an &#39;Amazing&#39; Start</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/post/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/post/week1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;ready-set-go&#34;&gt;Ready, Set, Go!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the airport Krakow, Poland with one of my fellow interns, Petr, a JV Czech staff member, Baru, and my intern director, Josh, via bus on Thursday, June 1st. We met up with our final team member Lydia who flew in from northern Ireland! From then on, we started on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H2edwpFxpg8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JV Amazing Race&lt;/a&gt;! The race took us throughout the city of Krakow, where we encountered challenges that were designed to build up team chemistry, uncover strengths and weaknesses of individuals, and teach us about Josiah Venture and Polish culture. After spending the night in a Krakow hostel and some more events Friday in Krakow, we tooke a bus to Český Těšín, where we finished the race (I felt like I had home court advantage low key).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you were wondering, we were in eighth place out of fourteen after day 1, and finished in fifth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some noteworthy race features were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finding specific plants in &lt;a href=&#34;https://ogrod.uj.edu.pl/english&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Botanical Garden of the Jagiellonian University&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Riding the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cracoweye.pl/en/home-english/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Krakow Eye&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Puzzles regarding famous Polish music composer&amp;rsquo;s Chopin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/2MSgFefjK0T7Iwjvr3OKqV?si=c69a8da111be40c5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nocturne No.20 in C sharp minor&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An epic scavenger hunt all over Krakow, with many items requiring us to talk to strangers,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking a picture from the overlook at Těšín,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning how to wash clothes in a sink in Český Těšín,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning the camp dance,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

















&lt;div class=&#34;gallery-grid&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
  
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;gallery-item gallery-item--medium&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-race&#34; href=&#34;https://carsonslater.com/media/albums/race/card.JPG&#34; &gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://carsonslater.com/media/albums/race/card_hu9dd1fdd79712fc29e9f6c16c44489b72_1006443_750x750_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;card.JPG&#34; width=&#34;563&#34; height=&#34;750&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
  
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;gallery-item gallery-item--medium&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-race&#34; href=&#34;https://carsonslater.com/media/albums/race/krakow.JPG&#34; &gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://carsonslater.com/media/albums/race/krakow_hu9eb3ca9273cc2b46053c3c2170086770_1628666_750x750_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;krakow.JPG&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;563&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
  
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;gallery-item gallery-item--medium&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-race&#34; href=&#34;https://carsonslater.com/media/albums/race/pyramid.JPG&#34; &gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://carsonslater.com/media/albums/race/pyramid_hu9dd1fdd79712fc29e9f6c16c44489b72_2930067_750x750_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;pyramid.JPG&#34; width=&#34;563&#34; height=&#34;750&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
  
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;gallery-item gallery-item--medium&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-race&#34; href=&#34;https://carsonslater.com/media/albums/race/race_bereal.JPG&#34; &gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://carsonslater.com/media/albums/race/race_bereal_hue5cfa4a500ca8e7f1113502e8eb7039b_185114_750x750_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; alt=&#34;race_bereal.JPG&#34; width=&#34;513&#34; height=&#34;750&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall this race was an opportunity for my to gel with my intern team, and I am so thankful for the memorable experience. Running and debriefing it was a huge opportunity to set ourselves up for success over the summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;intern-training&#34;&gt;Intern Training&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the race, I &amp;lsquo;ran into&amp;rsquo; one of the elders from my Arizona church, Doug Sandy! That was super cool. Doug was the leader of my first trip to Czechia last summer, and he was visiting the church we did our camp with last summer as a short-term team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-seeing-doug-and-our-friend-radek-in-český-těšín&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;screen reader text&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/week1/Doug_hucd1bb2f7f9e1dfeabb922a2333d78038_657728_0a86840172408117e6fa17310b7eff43.webp 400w,
               /post/week1/Doug_hucd1bb2f7f9e1dfeabb922a2333d78038_657728_a1142b1e54a19f774756797646350284.webp 760w,
               /post/week1/Doug_hucd1bb2f7f9e1dfeabb922a2333d78038_657728_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://carsonslater.com/post/week1/Doug_hucd1bb2f7f9e1dfeabb922a2333d78038_657728_0a86840172408117e6fa17310b7eff43.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;571&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Seeing Doug and our friend Radek in Český Těšín.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with we traveled to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
χάριτος καἰ εἰρήνη,&lt;br&gt;
(grace and peace)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;- Carson&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Model of Discipleship</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/post/discipleship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/post/discipleship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last summer, I visited the Czech Republic for the first time, and it was a great experience. We partnered with a church near the Polish border and helped with their annual English Camp. Thankfully, we did not just dive straight into the camp, unprepared. We did months of preparation on the front end of the trip, and even a couple days of training in Prague upon arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During our training, we were not only given time to overcome jet lag, but we were also introduced to Josiah Venture&amp;rsquo;s discipleship training material. I thought it would be helpful to share it with you all since it is the abstract paradigm through which I will be operating this summer as I minister to high school students!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a disclaimer, the first two of these challenges first happen to people who have not yet repented and believed (i.e. nonbelievers). Every person who is in Christ encounters these five challenges in their life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-five-challenges-of-christ&#34;&gt;The Five Challenges of Christ&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so obviously Jesus gave more than five challenges to disciples and others alike during the incarnation, but this framework has been what Josiah Venture has been using to train others to disciple during their camps ministry. I have found it very digestible, actionable, and easy to remember. I think it is cool too because I see parallels between Jesus&amp;rsquo;s words in Scripture and a Biblical Theology of Mission (spoiler alert).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-come-and-see&#34;&gt;1. Come and See&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first chapter of John, before Jesus began His ministry, we saw Him calling men to look at and entertain what He was doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[Jesus] said to them, &amp;lsquo;Come and you will see.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus (God incarnate) was drawing people to Himself. Is this new? Nope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about ancient Israel! They had a &amp;rsquo;limited&amp;rsquo; mission - to be a covenant community designed to mediate the presence of God on a sinful and rebellious earth. Israel did not reject foreigners dwelling among them, insofar as these foreigners did not lead the Israelites astray, but they were certainly not evangelistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for discipleship in my life to take place, I must first come and see what God is doing. How can I give a reason for the hope that is within me, if I have not begun personally witness what the Lord is doing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-repent-and-believe&#34;&gt;2. Repent and Believe&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discipleship does not stop with acknowledging God. Anyone who is in Christ is a new creation! When Jesus came to earth, He began His ministry saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The time is fulfilled, and the kingdom of God is at hand; repent and believe the gospel.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is this mysterious &amp;lsquo;kingdom&amp;rsquo; language Jesus is using? Why is it grounds to repent and believe the gospel?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is because the kingdom life is the life Jesus himself embodied and inaugurated.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, Jesus could say that &amp;rsquo;the kingdom of God is at hand&amp;rsquo; because &lt;em&gt;He&lt;/em&gt; was standing in their midst. Jesus not only made the perfect atonement for the sin of humanity, but He also embodied the lives God designed His people to live. Because the embodiment of the kingdom life was at hand, the kingdom of God was also at hand by extension. This is why when He started his ministry, He invited people to take on this kingdom life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for us to take on this new life, repentance is necessary. A godly sorrow for sin, and a turning away from things that displease God are key components of this. A bold faith in the truth and power of the gospel is of equal importance. Only then, when I understand what life with and in Christ means, can I begin to show others what it is about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-follow-me&#34;&gt;3. Follow Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As Jesus went on from there, He saw a man called Matthew, sitting in the tax collector’s booth; and He said to him, &amp;lsquo;Follow Me!&amp;rsquo; And he got up and followed Him. Then it happened that as Jesus was reclining at the table in the house, behold, many tax collectors and sinners came and were dining with Jesus and His disciples.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repentance and belief in the gospel are not a single, one-time events. Perhaps you can argue that the &lt;em&gt;resolution&lt;/em&gt; to repent and believe in the gospel is, but repentance and belief are daily decisions. When someone consistently makes the daily decision to repent and believe in the gospel with a genuine sincerity, one can say they are following Jesus!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following Jesus requires faithfulness. This component of faithfulness pertains to steadfastness. We can be faithful in one sense, where we believe in the gospel, but we can also be faithful in the other sense, where we had steadfast, unwavering belief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this phase a person begins to understand what life with God truly looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-fish-for-men&#34;&gt;4. Fish for Men&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I too can invite people to &amp;lsquo;come and see&amp;rsquo; what God is doing &amp;ndash; both on a personal and corporate level. This is one way we can mediate the presence of God on earth, as His royal priesthood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And [Jesus] said to them, &amp;lsquo;Follow me, and I will make you fishers of men.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This invitation to &amp;lsquo;fish for men,&amp;rsquo; is a challenge to invite people to come and see, repent and believe, and follow Jesus!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite examples in Scripture of this is the first four of these challenges in action, demonstrated in two verses. Paul writes to Timothy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You then, my child, be strengthened by the grace that is in Christ Jesus, and what you have heard from me in the presence of many witnesses entrust to faithful men who will be able to teach others also.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is precisely the verse we used to name the podcast that my friends started at my church in Arizona (shameless plug - click &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to listen on Spotify)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this idea of entrusting what we know about follow God to others new? Nope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s check out Deuteronomy 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You shall therefore lay up these words of mine in your heart and in your soul, and you shall bind them as a sign in your hand, and they shall be as frontlets between your eyes. You shall teach them to your children, talking of them when you are sitting in your house, and when you are walking by the way, and when you lie down, and when you rise. You shall write them on the doorposts of your house and on your gates&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a new idea! Propagation of the truth and kingdom life amongst humanity is a key part of God&amp;rsquo;s plan to restore Creation. Fishing for men plays a critical role in this plan!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-send-them-out&#34;&gt;5. Send Them Out&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the resurrection, Jesus visited His disciples, and He said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Peace be with you. As the Father has sent me, even so I am sending you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last challenge Jesus has with respect to discipleship is to send your disciples out. Just as we were once sent, we also need to send out those whom we have walked with. This challenge gives us all the more reason to train them up in the way they should go, because they will need to be equipped with a robust understanding of the things of God, and more importantly, a deep love for Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this post gives you a glimpse into what things we are trained to do in our internship. To be honest, this material was mostly things I digested last summer on my short-term trip, with a little bit of extra synthesis on my part. Hopefully, you gleaned something from this post, and are able to implement this into your life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
χάριτος καἰ εἰρήνη,&lt;br&gt;
(grace and peace)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;- Carson&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 1:35-40&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark 1:15&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Union with Christ&lt;/em&gt;, Rankin Wilborne, p. 90.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 9:9-10&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 4:19&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Timothy 2:1-2&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deuteronomy 11:18-20&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 20:21&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>...And We&#39;re Off!</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/post/travel_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/post/travel_blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today marks day one of my summer in Europe! It as been quite a crazy couple of weeks for myself. I aspired to write a few posts between when I posted my last one and now; however, perpetual circumstance in this season of transition did not relent. Here are a few moments I was able to be a part of in the past couple of weeks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two beautiful weddings for some of my favorite people!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My own undergraduate commencement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My sister&amp;rsquo;s high school graduation (shout out to Carolyn).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tender coversations with friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Packing up everything I own to prepare to move to Texas after my JV internship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels as though my college graduation was yesterday, but at the same time, I was itching to get on the plane to Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;god-is-moving&#34;&gt;God is moving.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although my post-grad time has been short and I have scarcely had time to process and reflect, here are some things that God has been laying on my heart:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suffering and joy are intuitively thought of as inversely proportional. Although suffering does not ellicit a joyful response in of itself, there is a perspective toward suffering we obtain once we are united with Christ that shows us that it is God&amp;rsquo;s workmanship perfecting us, making us whole.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lately, I have been learning how to grieve well!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My missionary summer internship is &lt;strong&gt;so significant, but not ultimate&lt;/strong&gt;. It is also a part of God&amp;rsquo;s greater plan to redeem and restore humanity, just like your workday, or your friendships! We have a role to play in the main story, but we are not the main story.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This summer will be an amazing learning experience. I am so excited!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to abide in Christ, as I am united with Him in His death and resurrection. &lt;em&gt;Perichoresis&lt;/em&gt; is the theological term for how the persons of the trinity relates to each other. It is though of as a dance - I too want to dance with God in this beautiful, messy, but calculated manner, letting him lead me. My salvation is my invitation into this dance with God!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;looking-ahead&#34;&gt;Looking Ahead&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon touchdown in Prague I will (Lord willing) be picked up by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.josiahventure.com/people-and-places/czech-republic/4089&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Josh Dietz&lt;/a&gt;, my original connection to Josiah Venture, and I will hop on a train to Ostrava, Czechia. After spending the night with my intern director, I will head to Krakow on a bus to start the Josiah Venture Amazing Race, a part of intern training! Stay tuned for fun stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-invitation-to-prayer&#34;&gt;An Invitation to Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to invite you to prayer over:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My intern team as we learn how to encourage one another and work as a team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My intern director, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.josiahventure.com/people-and-places/czech-republic/3876&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Josh Nelson&lt;/a&gt;, as he will be leading us the whole summer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The camps ministry for Josiah Venture, and all of the students who are going to be coming to camp!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for partnering with me in my summer missionary internship!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
χάριτος καἰ εἰρήνη,&lt;br&gt;
(grace and peace)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;- Carson&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the Name of Jesus</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/post/nouwen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/post/nouwen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-i-read-this-book--preliminary-thoughts&#34;&gt;Why I read this book + preliminary thoughts.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a part of my internship preparation, my intern director, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.josiahventure.com/people-and-places/czech-republic/3876&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Josh Nelson&lt;/a&gt; (shout out to Josh) encouraged me to read Henry Nouwen&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;In the Name of Jesus&lt;/em&gt;. So, I decided to write this post to invite all who are praying for me into what I am processing before my internship!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the moment I picked up this book, I knew it would be a convicting read. For those who do not know, Henry Nouwen is a prominent scholar who specialized in Christian ministry and ministerial psychology. Prior to writing this book, he served as a faculty member at Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s, Yale&amp;rsquo;s and Harvard&amp;rsquo;s Divinity schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I allude to my sense of conviction? Well, the introduction recounts Nouwen&amp;rsquo;s decision to leave academia in exchange for priesthood within a
L&amp;rsquo;Arche community (click &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.larcheusa.org/about/impact/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about L&amp;rsquo;Arche).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make matters more intense, the day I began to read this book, my pastor had literally given a sermon on how God is the one who reminds us of the dignity of the vulnerable, and that people&amp;rsquo;s humanity does not come from their accomplishments, wealth, social capital, or abilities to aquire these things. A person&amp;rsquo;s embodiment is enough to warrant dignity, because it means they have the Imago Dei! So I digress, I was interested to read this book and hear Nouwen&amp;rsquo;s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also drawn in because I personally was invited to visit and spend an evening with a L&amp;rsquo;Arche community my freshman year of college. Anecdotally, I remember being uncomfortable the whole time, but God has used those memories to redeem and formulate not only a posture of love toward the vulnerable but also a deep commitment to uphold the dignity of handicapped people. Looking back on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1SDFdjrkKMO6uW6tF8JuQ5yig__c1lmtG/edit?usp=sharing&amp;amp;ouid=106641034707807322739&amp;amp;rtpof=true&amp;amp;sd=true&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reflection assignment&lt;/a&gt;, I have come so far, but if I could rewrite that assignment again, I would iterate that we would do well to have constant exposure from all kinds of people in our lives, including the mentally handicapped. They provide a piece of the Imago Dei that we would not otherwise have known, and they provide opportunities for us to invite them into Christian community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-struck-me&#34;&gt;What Struck Me&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;being-relevant&#34;&gt;Being &amp;lsquo;Relevant&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first section of the book, Nouwen describes the insecurities he experienced upon entering the L&amp;rsquo;Arche community. Being an academic with some of the brightest students the world has to offer, he describes deeply feeling the contrast. He writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not being able to use any of the skills that have proved so practical in the past was a real source of anxiety. I was suddenly faced with my naked self, open for affirmations and rejections, hugs and punches, smiles and tears, all dependent simply on how I was perceived at the moment. In a way, it seemed as though I was starting my life all over again.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I deeply resonated with this, feeling similarly about exiting a context recently where I spend so much time and had many talents (i.e. playing baseball). The truth I reflected upon while engaging this writing is that nothing is wasted, even though sometimes I feel I have had no preparation for the things being thrown at me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nouwen took this notion a step further, to point out how he wanted to give into the temptation to rely on his accolates and be &amp;lsquo;relevant.&amp;rsquo; The thing is about L&amp;rsquo;Arche communities though, is that being a Harvard professor does not help you acquire much social capital. Stepping into this new community for Nouwen was an opportunity to fall back on His true identity as a Son of God, rather than an accomplished academic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can anticipate myself experiencing this same temptation this summer in a foreign culture. I do not think that most students at my camps will care that I played NCAA baseball, or am entering a Statistics PhD program. These are great things, but temporal, transient features of my short time on this side of heaven. I pray I can meet students where they are at, giving up my desire to be &amp;lsquo;relevant.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;searching-for-love-in-the-wrong-places&#34;&gt;Searching for Love in the Wrong Places&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nouwen claims our desire to be &amp;lsquo;relevant&amp;rsquo; is inextricably tied to our desire to be loved. Naturally, we crave love from the people around us whom we deem significant in our lives (parents, children, spouses, friends), but Nouwen points out this love as secondary to the true love &amp;ndash; the &amp;ldquo;first love&amp;rdquo; found in our intimate relationship with God. Love within interpersonal relationships are often the source of frustration, resentment, and anger, but God&amp;rsquo;s love is untainted and abundantly more than sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The radical good news is that the second love is only a broken reflection of the first love, and that the first love is offered to us by a God, in whom there are no shadows. Jesus&amp;rsquo;s heart is the incarnation of the shadow-free first love of God.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it truly mean to live each day, knowing you are beloved?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nouwen takes to mysticism as the answer. (Christian) Mysticism is where a person is keenly aware of the love of God, via various spiritual practices. I believe Julian of Norwich is the default mystic most people think of, knowing about her work, &lt;em&gt;Revelations of Divine Love&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nouwen would say that the Christian leader is truly after the heart of Christ, the &amp;ldquo;first love.&amp;rdquo; They are secure in their identity as adopted and beloved, and they are consumed with the desire dwell in the presence of God (like in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bible.com/bible/111/PSA.84.10-12.NIV&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Psalm 84:10-12&lt;/a&gt;!). This desire for intimacy with God manifests itself in contemplative, introspective, and worshipful prayer. It bears the fruit of wisdom and sound judgement, going beyond moral behavior modification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But when we are securely rooted in personal intimacy with the source of life, it will be impossible to remain flexible without being relativistic, convinced without being rigid, willing to confront without being offensive, gentle and forgiving without being soft, and true witnesses without being manipulative.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we are in step with the Spirit of God, secure in the &amp;ldquo;first love,&amp;rdquo; we know we need not look for approval from man, or anywhere else (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bible.com/bible/59/gal.1.10&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Galatians 1:10&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;serving-alongside-others&#34;&gt;Serving Alongside Others&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ministry is not a solo endeavor. Although this seems trivial, I cannot help but confess that I resonate with Nouwen when he admits to feeling like he can provide all things for all people. He calls it the temptation to be &amp;lsquo;spectacular.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being &amp;lsquo;spectacular&amp;rsquo; is not inherently a bad thing. Our excellence can prove to be a positive witness for Christ in certain cases. The problem lies when we begin to inwardly perceive that the burden rests on &lt;em&gt;us&lt;/em&gt; as individuals. We can be tempted to do something spectacular &amp;ldquo;on our own&amp;rdquo; for the sake of receiving applause. This sense of individual heroism can puff up, but Christ reminds us that doing ministry in community is better. If we as the church are truly co-laborers in Christ, serving together is a way for us to operate as a functioning body, rather than isolated individuals. In practice we may feel this is fulfilled in church activity, but if our posture is not yearning for this, we might be seeking to exalt ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past year, I met with a group of young men every Monday night to study different facets of biblical masculinity. All of us were college students except our leader, who is the Dean of Residence Life at Wheaton College. One of my biggest takeaways from the group is this idea of living a &amp;lsquo;confessional life.&amp;rsquo; Confessing even the &amp;lsquo;smallest&amp;rsquo; sins, or even the preceding temptations to others enables us to combat their normalization. Nouwen writes that confession enables us to abandon our pride, and subsequently our sense of individual heroism. Perhaps this is one of the things John was trying to draw out when he wrote, saying&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living a confessional lifestyle is a grace from the Lord to keep us sober-minded. Not only is it inviting people into our brokenness, but also it can keep us humble when we want to grow puffed up. The bottom line is, we were not built to serve alone. We were also not built for one-sided ministry. Nouwen writes,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is Jesus who heals, not I; Jesus who speaks words of truth, not I; Jesus who is Lord, not I.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that he who waters will himself be watered (&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/111/PRO.11.25&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Proverbs 11:25&lt;/a&gt;). Hence, we must consider that true ministry is mutual. Not only can we choose to invite people to serve alongside us, but we can also choose to acknowledge that the people we are serving are doing us just as much of a service by allowing us to serve them. The Lord can use that for His glory and our good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The mystery of ministy is that we have been chosen to make our own limited and very conditional love the gateway for the unlimited and unconditional love of God.&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;power-dynamics&#34;&gt;Power Dynamics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I come to understand that all ministry is mutual, and that my sense of individual heroism is faulty, I begin to see that ministry is not an opportunity to exercise power over others, but rather an opportunity to embrace lowliness. Jesus&amp;rsquo;s incarnation was a perfect example of Himself meeting us where we are at. He condescended to humanity, that they might grow in intimacy with Himself. We too, albeit limited, can meet people where they are at, but we do not condescend. We are beggars showing other beggars where the food is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nouwen wrote of his lamentation over power complexes in churches. He craves for church leaders to abandon their condescending leadership styles, and to transition from &amp;rsquo;leading&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;being led.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It seems easier to be God than to love God, easier to control people than to love people, easier to own life than to love life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we pause, and we consider the God we are serving and leading other toward, we know that it is not we ourselves who are drawing people. God draws people to Himself, and we are the instruments of mercy being led by Him. We do well when we walk cognizant of this. Deep, theological reflection is a grace from God whereby the believer can regain their view of the proverbial forest in the midst of the trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Christian leader thinks, speaks, and acts in the name of Jesus, [&amp;hellip;] To be such a leader is to discern from moment to moment how God acts in human history and how the personal, communal, national, and international events that occur in our lives can make us more sensitive to the ways we are led to the cross and through the cross to the resurrection.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-hard-hitting-questions&#34;&gt;The Hard-Hitting Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-this-book-asking-of-me&#34;&gt;What is this book asking of me?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Henri Nouwen&amp;rsquo;s honest confession of what he learned serving at a L&amp;rsquo;Arche community is refreshing and challenging because He asks the reader to give up being relevant, being heroic in the most prideful sense, and lastly the desire to be powerful. After being asked to consider these things, I have personally been able to bring these temptations into the light, and to be aware of them as I head into a summer of vocational ministry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-does-this-book-make-manifesthint-at-the-gospel-lifestyle&#34;&gt;How does this book make manifest/hint at the gospel lifestyle?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book really incorporates the gospel by bringing to light common lies Christians believe as they lead others to Christ, and demonstrating how they are actually contrary to the gospel. It illuminates ways Christians are failing to die to themselves, as Christ died for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-should-read-this-book&#34;&gt;Who should read this book?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feels like a cop-out answer, but any person seeking to dive deeper into Christian leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-is-this-content-relevantimportant&#34;&gt;Why is this content relevant/important?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This content is important because it stands opposed to what charisma-driven leadership teaches today. Nouwen&amp;rsquo;s brutal honesty was very relatable and refreshing to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summarize-this-book-in-one-thought&#34;&gt;Summarize this book in one thought.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading like Jesus looks a lot different than what our culture tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;concluding-thoughts&#34;&gt;Concluding Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I would definitely recommend engaging with Nouwen&amp;rsquo;s thoughts! Feel free to reach out if anything in this article struck you, especially if you want to process it further!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fully Funded!</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/post/funded/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/post/funded/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-have-great-news&#34;&gt;I have great news!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the grace of God, I have been able to raise all of the necessary funds to spend the entire summer in the Czech Republic! Thank you to everyone who chose to contribute financially! I want to continue to invite you into deeper relationship via mutual prayer and encouragement. Praise be to God! He is so faithful. This season has been a season full of His provision. Here are some things you can be praying for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pray for the missionaries who are promoting the camps right now in the Czech Republic!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pray for the churches who are putting together the camps. There are a lot of logistical details that need to be worked out. Pray that the Lord will bring ease and peace to those people making those decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pray that the other interns on my team can be supported! If you were planning on giving to me but have not yet done so, I encourage you to support the other two interns who will be serving with me throughout the summer, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.josiahventure.com/give-form/?designation=49767846-1ca9-4e5a-a0db-8b6742d781fe&amp;amp;user=54334&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Petr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.josiahventure.org.uk/uk-giving?id=54081&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lydia&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pray for intern directors who are organizing provisions for my team and myself, that they would be able to do this with ease!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lastly, pray for the war in Ukraine 🇺🇦. We as Christians would do well to petition the Lord for peace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am so excited to see how the Lord is going to work this summer. I am also grateful that He has invited all of us into participating in His kingdom work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;having-bold-faith&#34;&gt;Having &lt;strong&gt;BOLD&lt;/strong&gt; Faith&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over my spring break (a month ago), I was feeling the weight of my future. I was wrestling with the uncertainty that lay ahead of me. My good friend would say that I was aware God is on His throne, but I was not trusting in that His plan is what is best for me and for His glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While in Arizona a little over a month ago, I went for a walk. I was praying and was prompted to read Mark 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The narrative begins in verse 14. Jesus was just coming down the mountain after the transfiguration, when he was bombarded by a crowd of people. They were originally surrounding the disciples who had not ascended the mountain with Jesus. A demon-possessed boy was brought before Jesus, who was told his disciples could not cast the demon out of the boy. Verses 20-24 read:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They brought the boy to Him. When he saw Him, immediately the spirit threw him into a convulsion, and falling to the ground, he began rolling around and foaming at the mouth. And He asked his father, &amp;ldquo;How long has this been happening to him?&amp;rdquo; And he said, &amp;ldquo;From childhood. It has often thrown him both into the fire and into the water to destroy him. But if You can do anything, take pity on us and help us!&amp;rsquo; And Jesus said to him, ‘If You can? All things are possible to him who believes.&amp;rsquo; Immediately the boy’s father cried out and said, `I do believe; help my unbelief.&#39;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this, I wept. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but notice how the boy&amp;rsquo;s father had said &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;If You can do anything&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; I was faced with the reality that too often, when I ask the Lord for things, I possess a posture of doubt. &amp;ldquo;God, &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; you can&amp;hellip;[insert petition].&amp;rdquo; The problem with this is if I truly believe sanctification looks like my desires growing more consistent with the Lord&amp;rsquo;s desires, then I should have no problem believing that God can and will grant my petitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to be mindful to walk the line between being comfortable and full of faith in my prayers, yet acknowledging that God is so much more than a granter of requests. Our end game is to be united with Him in His death and resurrection, and to embody Him to others so that they might come to know Him. Part of this looks like our desires becoming His. If this is the case, I can boldly approach His throne with full confidence, acknowledging that He is faithful! (Hebrews 4:16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-be-to-god&#34;&gt;Thanks be to God&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks be to God for this opportunity to be a part of this summer ministry. The Lord is more than capable of anything we can ask or imagine. I want to thank everyone who has chosen to support me via financial provisions or prayer, and I would love to invite you into more prayer. Stay tuned for more prayer updates, and in the meantime, let me know how I can pray for you in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://carsonslater.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt; on the homepage!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
χάριτος καἰ εἰρήνη,&lt;br&gt;
(grace and peace)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;- Carson&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Biblical Theology of Mission?</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/post/bibtheomissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/post/bibtheomissions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-write-this&#34;&gt;Why Write This?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greetings! As I am spending my summer doing missions in Europe, and I wanted to dig a little bit deeper into how missions fits into God&amp;rsquo;s overarching plan to redeem humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would love to point out that although this article has everything to do with what I am doing this summer, it simultaneously has nothing to do with the specific particularities of my summer. My reflections on mission are simply an exercise of preparation as I gear up for the coming season. Hence, this post most definitely will feel a little more dry if you are expecting something personal. I hope you find that reflecting on God&amp;rsquo;s holistic plan introduces a new, vibrant lens that showcases the significance of our day to day ministry tasks we engage in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-point&#34;&gt;The Point&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing theology for the sake of the intellectual stimulation, or knowledge acquisition, can be profitable and well intented; however, the reason I write this article is to invite people to &lt;em&gt;know God&lt;/em&gt;. Knowing God is infinitely more valuable than having wrestled with all theological topics and concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theology is an  opportunity to better understand and seek God for the sake of intimacy. My prayer for this article is that if you read this, you may be introduced to a new or better understanding of the epic plan for God&amp;rsquo;s people, and maybe catch a new glimpse of the Planner Himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-biblical-theology&#34;&gt;What is Biblical Theology?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I had heard the phrase, &amp;lsquo;Biblical Theology&amp;rsquo; in a Christian circle. Naively, my knee jerk reaction was: &amp;ldquo;Isn&amp;rsquo;t all Theology Biblical?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
It turns out that I was wrong, at least in one sense. What I ended up learning is that there are different ways of doing theology. There are different approaches that can be taken to learning about God. To quote Andrew David Naselli,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Biblical theology is a way of analyzing and synthesizing the Bible that makes organic, salvation-historical connections with the whole canon on its own terms, especially how the Old and New Testaments progress, integrate, and climax in Christ.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a shortcut, the framework I like to use to think about biblical theology is by comparing it to other ways of doing theology. At its core, biblical theology, systematic theology, and historical theology are all avenues of studying God, but they are distinct in their own right. Historical theology is beautiful because it heavily considers and analyzes church history and theological development. Systematic theology presupposes questions and goes to Scriputre for answers, for the sake of building a robust framework to think about God. Biblical Theology, on the other hand, is exegesis in light of the whole Scripture. Biblical Theology uses the historical narrative of the Bible, and allows Scripture to raise questions about God on its own terms. It consults the development of the redemptive narrative for answers, and engages typologies to trace big thematic elements in the Bible. This is why Biblical Theology is of particular interest to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-biblical-theology-of-mission&#34;&gt;A Biblical Theology of Mission&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-few-disclaimers&#34;&gt;A Few Disclaimers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to put my cards on the table by acknowledging that I am by no means a theological scholar, rather I am just a humble college student. I may grow excited in my writing about specific salvation-historical connections, but at the end of the day, there are some sobering facts to acknowledge about the mission of the people of God:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is sovereign. (Ps. 115:3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humanity cannot save themselves. (Eph. 2:1-3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God invites humanity into reconciliation, not only restoring humanity to a relationship with Himself, but inviting us to become co-laborers with Him. (2 Cor. 5:17-19)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The entirety of the people of God will be able to worship God in unity with Christ, resulting in passionate praise for all eternity. (Rev. 5:9-10)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God invites His people to participate in this outpouring of salvation by enabling them to become lights in a dark world; the people of God are not the source of the light, but the conduit. (2 Cor. 4:5-7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more disclaimer is that the discipline of Biblical Theology is like a game of pick-up-sticks. It is hard to trace one particular theme without disturbing or untangling it from other themes in Scripture, as they are heavily interwoven. Hence, in this article I may gloss over really important facts that are relevant but mostly relate to other themes in Scripture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-original-comission&#34;&gt;The Original Comission&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When God created the earth, He created His image within a garden sanctuary. It was the place where the people had &lt;em&gt;intimate communion with God&lt;/em&gt;. Afterwards, humanity reject this calling by imitating the serpent. Ultimately, God still wanted to magnify Himself in the universe, with the people that He had originally created. After cursing the earth, God still promised to deliver His people from their rebellion, restoring them to be right-working image-bearers of Himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-blessing-for-all-nations&#34;&gt;A Blessing for All Nations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get a glimpse for God&amp;rsquo;s plan to reconcile all peoples to Himself when He commissions Abram to go forth to possess a specific portion of Canaan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Now the Lord said to Abram, “Go forth from your country, And from your relatives And from your father’s house, To the land which I will show you; And I will make you a great nation, And I will bless you, And make your name great; And so you shall be a blessing; And I will bless those who bless you, And the one who curses you I will curse. And in you all the families of the earth will be blessed.&amp;quot;&amp;rsquo; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people are quick to point out how in Abram &amp;ldquo;all the families of the earth will be blessed.&amp;rdquo; What tends to be overlooked is that God states that Abram is to be a blessing &lt;strong&gt;in the land to which He is going&lt;/strong&gt;. Dr. Jason S. DeRouchie notes that God&amp;rsquo;s covenant with Abram required that He go to Canaan, so that He may become a great nation (Israel), but that eventually one day Abram (or perhaps His representative) would be a blessing to all nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;come-and-see&#34;&gt;Come and See&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abram then became Abraham, and His offspring endured 400+ years of slavery in Egypt. Following the Exodus, God used this offspring (again, the nation Israel) to mediate God&amp;rsquo;s presence and blessings to the surrounding nations. Through radical submission, Abraham&amp;rsquo;s offspring would serve as holy representatives to a needy world. Israel as a nation was not evangelistic; their mission was to cultivate a covenant community that was not exclusive to foreigners. Hence, Israel&amp;rsquo;s culture, customs and laws served as an invitation to the world to &amp;lsquo;come and see&amp;rsquo; what God was doing. This was Israel&amp;rsquo;s &amp;rsquo;limited&amp;rsquo; mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;visions-of-hope-and-reconciliation&#34;&gt;Visions of Hope and Reconciliation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people of God now are living in covenant community in the land, and prophecies begin to emerge and reminding Israel that God&amp;rsquo;s promises were to bring good news for all nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the Lord all the offspring of Israel will be justified and will glory.” &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blessing is depicted in Isaiah by the servant songs. These songs depict a &amp;lsquo;servant&amp;rsquo; that ministers to both Israel and the nations. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This royal servant would&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enjoy God&amp;rsquo;s presence and would fulfill his mission to bring justice to the nations, (&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/100/ISA.42.1-4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Isa. 42:1-4&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;engage in a ministry of mercy, (&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/100/ISA.51.4-5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Isa. 51:4-5&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;guide the lost, (&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/100/ISA.61.1-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Isa. 61:1-3&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serve as a covenant mediator,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;open the eyes of the blind and deliver the captive, (&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/100/ISA.42.6-7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Isa.42:6-7&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and preach the good news of God&amp;rsquo;s victory over evil and God&amp;rsquo;s saving grace. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/100/ISA.52.7-10&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Isa. 52:7-10&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/100/ISA.61.1-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; 61:1-3&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only in Isaiah do we see God&amp;rsquo;s heart for the nations, but also in Jonah. Many like to pigeonhole Jonah as the missionary archetype, but I would particularly argue that He was appointed for a specific mission rather than as a New Covenant missionary. Jonah serves as an example of &lt;em&gt;Israel&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; outreach to the nations, but is helpful to acknowledge in a Biblical Theology of mission because he serves as a reminder that God is always interested in the whole world. This is all despite His choosing of Israel to mediate for Him initially within the salvation-historical narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-new-covenant-in-christ&#34;&gt;The New Covenant in Christ&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we find is that Jesus arrives as the incarnate God, and He fulfills these prophecies of the servant in Isaiah. Not only does He accomplish this, but He fulfills the Law, conquers death, and institutes the New Covenant.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In this New Covenant, the people of God take on posture of faith, which leads to obedience and extends worship beyond the walls of the temple. The people of God are no longer exclusively Jews, but also Gentiles, making salvation available for all peoples of all nations.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;go-and-tell&#34;&gt;Go and Tell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Jesus&amp;rsquo;s last statements before the ascension was the Great Commission. Before sending His disciples - the people of God - out into the world to teach all that He had taught, He reminds His disciples that &amp;ldquo;all authority on heaven and earth has been given to&amp;rdquo; Himself.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Christians on mission do well to observe the omnipotence and authority of their Master, their Savior Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This commission amends to the overall disposition of the people of God as a &amp;lsquo;come and see&amp;rsquo; covenant community to also a &amp;lsquo;go and tell&amp;rsquo; mindset. In the Old Testament, God&amp;rsquo;s people are a kingdom of priests and a holy nation. Now the church, filled and empowered by the Holy Spirit, also acts as God&amp;rsquo;s dynamic living temple-sanctuary who aims to shine lights in a dark world. The church was created to show the rest of the world who their beautiful Creator and Sustainer is. The church truly is the fulfillment of Acts 1:8, where Jesus before His ascension states that His disciples will receive the outpouring of the Holy Spirit, and go to the ends of the earth to bear witness and testimony about the Lord. &lt;em&gt;The church was made for mission.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-his-kingdom-comes&#34;&gt;When His Kingdom Comes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salvation truly does belong to the Lamb who sits on the throne.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; One of the most beautiful passages of Scripture is in Revelation 5:9. Here John the apostle describes a vision where people from every nation, tribe, and tongue are worshiping God. As John Piper once wrote, &amp;lsquo;Missions exists because worship doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&amp;rsquo; One reason the kingdom of God possesses beauty is because it is multi-ethnic! God has invited His people, the church, into this mission of self-revelation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As God&amp;rsquo;s image bearers rejected their duties to bear God&amp;rsquo;s image, God enacted a plan to magnify Himself in the universe. Seeking reconciliation with all peoples, God promised that the seed of the woman would crush the head of the serpent, whom the people imitated. He promised to bless all the nations of the earth through the line of Abram, and build up a covenant nation called to be set apart for God&amp;rsquo;s purposes. This community was to be a nation of holy priests so that all other nations might &amp;lsquo;come and see&amp;rsquo; what God was doing in Israel. After continual promises of restoration, God sent the Messiah as He promised. This suffering servant instituted the New Covenant, adding a &amp;lsquo;go and tell&amp;rsquo; posture to the people of God, outpouring His power onto them through the Holy Spirit, all so that the world may worship Him one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;application&#34;&gt;Application&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking holistically about mission through a biblical theological framework must not be mistaken for a thought experiment! Biblical Theology is a tool that can prevent Christians from missing the forest for the trees. Not only does this help us observe God&amp;rsquo;s overarching plan for His people, but it uncovers His heart for humanity. Additionally, seeing the entirety of God&amp;rsquo;s plan for His people serves as a humbling reminder for how small, yet crucial of a role each individual plays in the plan. In the midst of the knitty-gritty details of our respective ministries, such as serving at an English Camp in Europe, we can be reminded that nothing can stand in the way of God as He accomplishes His plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/40-Questions-About-Biblical-Theology/dp/0825445604/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=40&amp;#43;questions&amp;#43;about&amp;#43;biblical&amp;#43;theology&amp;amp;qid=1678473716&amp;amp;sprefix=40&amp;#43;questions&amp;#43;about&amp;#43;bibl%2Caps%2C124&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;40 Questions About Biblical Theology, Chapter 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/100/GEN.12.1-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Genesis 12:1-3&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/100/ISA.45.25&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Isaiah 45:25&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Isaiah 42:1–4; Isaiah 49:1–6; Isaiah 50:4–11; and Isaiah 52:13–53:12&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Mark 1:14-15, Luke 22:14-20&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Isaiah 11:10, Galatians 3:8, 14, 16, 29&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Matthew 28:19-20&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Revelation 7:9-10&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Heartbeat Behind Support Raising</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/post/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/post/support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I prepare for the upcoming summer, I have been tasked with raising $5400 of support by May 1; that gives me just over a month to raise the funds from the time of posting this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-temptation&#34;&gt;The Temptation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I confess that as someone who is supposed to be paying attention to the quantity of funding coming in, it is very easy to uphold a reductionist attitude toward support raising. It can easily be boiled down to be a means to an end. This is such a counter-intuitive way to think about it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I neglect the people on the other side of my invitation for support, I miss out on so many things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Whoever brings blessing will be enriched, and one who waters will himself be watered.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;partnership&#34;&gt;Partnership&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at one of the first-ever New Covenant short-term missionaries in Scripture. His name was Epaphroditus, and a short blurb was written about him in Philippians 2:25-30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Paul, Epaphroditus was sent to him in Rome by the church of Philippi, and he was able to deliver necessary supplies to Paul to assist with his ministry. Although it does not specify how, Epaphroditus nearly dies of illness while on this journey. I want to highlight what Paul says about him though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have thought it necessary to send to you Epaphroditus my brother and fellow soldier, and your messenger and minister to my need.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epaphroditus was used as the tangible component of the church of Philippi&amp;rsquo;s partnership with Paul. Recall that in chapter 1 of Philippians,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Paul writes about his partnership with the church of Philippi. Here are some of the things he writes about them as his supporters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every time he thinks of them, he thanks God. (v. 3-4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He considers them partners in the gospel. (v. 5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He reminds the church of the perfect work of Jesus in them being brought to completion via sanctification. (v. 6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He considers them partakers of grace. (v. 7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hope and prayer is that if you choose to partner with me in prayer or with financial support, please let me know and reach out! I would love to pray for you as you partake in the grace that God has bestowed upon you and others in your proximity. We can partner together to make known the riches of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s kindness. I certainly have been forgiven much, so it only makes sense that I love others much by sharing a salvific message with them, to the glory of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reducing the supporter-supportee relationship to a transaction yields minimal fruit, if any. There are so many blessings that come from that rich fellowship, and the Paul-Philippi example is no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-invitation-to-co-labor&#34;&gt;An Invitation to Co-Labor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heartbeat behind support raising is to invite people into ministry through prayer and financial support. I hope to engage in mutual encouragement and prayer to labor and yearn for the kingdom of God on this earth &lt;strong&gt;together&lt;/strong&gt;, and the for redemption of the lost. I pray that reports of my efforts would elicit or inspire a Spirit-driven desire within you to engage in gospel work where you are at. Thank you to everyone who has set such a phenomenal example for me in my upbringing of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bold-faith&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BOLD&lt;/strong&gt; Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that if God is bigger than all I can ask or imagine, and that if He calls me His son, He would have no problem with me asking for great things in &lt;strong&gt;bold faith&lt;/strong&gt;. God is investing in His children to yield a return of 30, 60, or 100 fold! Investors want their investments to yield 100-fold returns! That is exactly why I am inviting everyone I can into this partnership, asking for as much as they are able to give cheerfully. I am so excited to see what God does this summer when He chooses to move in the regions of central and eastern Europe. I truly hold onto this exhoration in 2 Corinthians:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;&amp;ldquo;And God is able to make all grace abound to you, so that having all sufficiency in all things at all times, you may abound in every good work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nice-theory-but-what-about-practice&#34;&gt;Nice Theory, but What About Practice?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How will I invite you into this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already received one, I&amp;rsquo;d love to send you a support letter! It gives details of my trip, what I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing, and what to pray for as I prepare for my summer missionary internship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, if you feel led, I invite you to give! You can click &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.josiahventure.com/give-form/?designation=689836c4-8b96-407c-afb1-27c679d96029&amp;amp;user=53992&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to find the online donation portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would be remissed if our contact stopped at those two pathways. I encourage you to go to the home page and fill out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://carsonslater.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt; with a message desribing how I can stay in contact with you. I can also add you to the subscriber list for when I post for this blog! This blog will be updated weekly while I am in Europe, so stay tuned for prayer requests!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, my phone number is on the contact page as well. I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you with any prayer requests you have that I can be praying for. This will help me be aware of what God is doing in your life, and how I can encourage you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My cell phone number is +1 (480) 320-8898. Text me anytime!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-am-fighting-for-this-posture&#34;&gt;How I am Fighting for This Posture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josiah Venture actually had me take a small reflective course on support raising. Support raising can be uncomfortable because you don&amp;rsquo;t see the other side of what you believe God is calling you into, until you get there. In other words, I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I will have all of my funds raised by May 1, but I know that God can provide. This is an opportunity to trust in His provision, even though I cannot see the outcome. This is inherently uncomfortable, but that is okay! In my support raising course, I was asked to chart out a few lies I was fighting to reject. I was then asked to rebuke those same lies with the truth. Here are some of the things I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lie 1&lt;/strong&gt;: I can control the things that truly aren&amp;rsquo;t within my control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Truth 1&lt;/strong&gt;: At the end of the day, I do not control how many people decide to support me, but I can be faithful by inviting them into this process and journey with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lie 2&lt;/strong&gt;: I can passively wait for God to provide support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Truth 2&lt;/strong&gt;: Faithfulness is an active posture. I still need to invite support from others, and trust God will take care of the rest. Money or prayer from others does not &amp;lsquo;fall out of the sky&amp;rsquo; in this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lie 3&lt;/strong&gt;: My prayers do not do anything in the support raising process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Truth 3&lt;/strong&gt;: Prayer is not preparation for the work. Prayer IS the work. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; God invites us to petition for His provision as an act of faith and worship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-expression-of-gratitude&#34;&gt;An Expression of Gratitude&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ι hope this post is able to unpack the nuance surrounding my support raising journey for you. I pray that as you consider joining what God is doing in Central and Eastern Europe, that God will begin to unveil things in your own heart, that you yourself may grow in intimacy with Him. He is the true fount of our salvation; He is our portion! Thanks be to God, for enabling us to co-labor with Him as broken yet mighty vessels of grace, by the power of His Holy Spirit. Thank you for taking the time to read this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
χάριτος καἰ εἰρήνη,&lt;br&gt;
(grace and peace)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;- Carson&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proverbs 11:25 &lt;em&gt;ESV&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philippians 2:25 &lt;em&gt;ESV&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philippians 1:3-7 &lt;em&gt;ESV&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians 9:8 &lt;em&gt;ESV&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oswald Chambers, &lt;em&gt;My Utmost for His Highest&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returning to Europe</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/post/returning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/post/returning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear reader,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that if you take the time to read this post, you may be encouraged to draw near to Jesus Christ, through whom are all things and to whom are all things. My prayer is that you grow in the assurance of your calling to reconciliation with God and His mission on this earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-prior-experiences&#34;&gt;My Prior Experiences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last summer, I had the amazing opportunity to join a team from my church in Arizona on a trip to the Czech Republic where we partnered with a local Czech church to facilitate an English Camp. At this camp, we shared the gospel with youth in their area through various talks and small group discussions in the evenings. I embarked on the trip with an awareness of Europe’s larger attitude toward Protestant Christianity, having previously served in Romania three times, but I came back to the States with a yearning to return, in order that I may continue to walk in the good works the Lord has prepared for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am excited to write to you now to inform you that God has provided an opportunity for me to return to the Czech Republic, only for a longer period of time. After going to Europe to engage people with the gospel four times, I cannot deny the strategy I see behind living in Europe as a Christian, let alone serving alongside missionaries who are already actively working there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-why&#34;&gt;My &amp;lsquo;Why&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I currently attend college in a city that is ranked on this list for the most churches per capita in the world. I grew up less than a mile away from two large churches, and even a Presbyterian church to sweeten the deal. My experiences in Europe have shown me that a European mega-church usually consists of around 100 members, as opposed to the 2,000+ members that I am prone to visualize when I picture a stereotypical American mega-church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mention this to illustrate that in America, people actually have options of where they choose to go to church, which is not a reality everywhere in Europe. This disparity points to the notion that there is much work to be done in exposing people to the gospel in Europe. There are so many people in Europe living a life that has never been exposed to Jesus in a personal way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The population of the Czech Republic is approximately 0.737% evangelical &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s right. Less than a percent. However, this percent has a growth rate of 0.3% per year! There are believers on the ground in this nation, and I am honored to be given the opportunity to walk alongside them for two and a half months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-posture&#34;&gt;My Posture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last summer, I was able to serve at English Camp with a Church in Český Těšín, CZ. I was coming out of a very heavy season of life, where I had just quit baseball (I had played for 13 years and gotten to the college level) and was convicted that I had used it as an means to glorify myself. I had been drawn to missions in high school before, but after coming to Wheaton, I was less mindful of it while pursuing other passions that I have since deemed as not conducive to spiritual growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was in this heavy season, one of my pastors at my church in Wheaton shared a verse with me before I left for Europe last summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For we are His workmanship, created in Christ Jesus for good works, which God prepared beforehand so that we would walk in them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
(Ephesians 2:10 NASB)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I was encouraged when I heard it, I had no clue how clear this would become while I was serving. I was able to reframe missions as my participation in building the most honorable kingdom - the kingdom of God. Missions was not the passion of my past, rather it was restored as a means by which I could walk in the good works God has prepared for me. I want to accept this invitation from the Lord to partake in His masterful building plan for His kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means am I saying that missions is the ONLY way to walk in the good works God has prepared for me. That would be to suppose the sacred-secular divide is real, which is not true. I just know that the Holy Spirit empowered me to get excited about sharing my first love with other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, I am going back. I am by no means sufficient to carry this out on my own, but I know God&amp;rsquo;s power is perfected in my weakness. I just need to act in faith and obedience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
χάριτος καἰ εἰρήνη,&lt;br&gt;
(grace and peace)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;- Carson&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. If you want to inquire or chat, please feel free to reach out on the contact form of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://carsonslater.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;home page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://globe.stratus.earth/country-explorer/CZE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Joshua Project via Stratus Earth&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my blog!</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-even-is-this&#34;&gt;What even is this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a place where I plan on sharing my thoughts, experienes, and things I have found to be encouragements in my life!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why&lt;/strong&gt;: This blog is inspired by my desire to encourage people to follow Jesus. More specifically, I was inspired by a practice my church group did when we were serving in the Czech Republic through an organization called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.josiahventure.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Josiah Venture&lt;/a&gt;, where we &lt;a href=&#34;https://fbcaz.com/all-good/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;blogged&lt;/a&gt; about our experiences to bring our local church body alongside us our Journey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To Whom&lt;/strong&gt;: The intended audience for this blog is anyone who is partnering with me in my endeavors to share the gospel with youth. While my intended audience is limited, this blog is actually for anyone and everyone! Please join in praying for me as I prepare to spend my summer as an intern with Josiah Venture!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-you-plan-on-posting-here&#34;&gt;What do you plan on posting here?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to share with you my experiences preparing for my JV summer internship, as well as my experiences during the internship. After my time in Czechía, I will be able to reflect on the things that God was showing me along the way!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I also have ambitions to publish some of my own writing here - mainly about books I want to review, ideas I want to share, and things I would love to invite you to consider!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-josiahventurehttpswwwjosiahventurecom&#34;&gt;What is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.josiahventure.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JosiahVenture&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josiah Venture is a para-church missions organization focused on raising up youth leaders in Central and Eastern Europe. Their mission statement can be found on their website, but I&amp;rsquo;ve retrieved it here for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&#34;This is the vision of Josiah Venture, a vision for a movement of God among the youth of Central and Eastern Europe that finds its home in the local church and transforms society. Our mission and calling is to equip young leaders to fulfill Christ’s commission by reaching and making disciples. More than just conversion, we want to see passionate followers of Jesus Christ, with a vision to reach and disciple their generation for him.&#34;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heartbeat behind Josiah Venture is actually derived from the story of King Josiah of Israel (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bible.com/bible/59/2CH.34.ESV&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;read here&lt;/a&gt;). He inherits the throne of Israel at age eight. He did what was right in the eyes of God, purged the nation of places reserved for idol worship, and sought to reorient the people to follow God once again. As an organization, Josiah Venture seeks to find and raise up more Josiah&amp;rsquo;s across Central and Eastern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-will-you-be-serving&#34;&gt;How will you be serving?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be serving alongside the current Josiah Venture missionaries that are already in Czechía by partnering with local churches to promote, plan, and facilitate English Camps across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-you-give-me-a-preview-of-what-this-will-look-like-somehow&#34;&gt;Can you give me a preview of what this will look like somehow?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t exactly look into the future, but I imagine it will look similar to the camp I served last summer, when my church in AZ partnered with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cbtesin.cz/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;local Czech church&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/h3TBU2FuNTE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope I anticipated the questions you might have. If not, feel free to contact me with more questions via the form on the home page. I was led to create this blog in December 2022, and it is super fun to finally see it come to fruition. Glory be to God, and may this page be one that is edifying to all who read it!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
My hope and prayer is that if you have chosen to let Jesus rule over your life, that you may be spurred on to love and good works (Hebrews 10:24), and that if you do not yet have Jesus as the ruler of your life, that you’d stick around for the sake of curiosity. After all, I’ll probably be posting more than just summer preparatory items on here! &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
χάριτος καἰ εἰρήνη,&lt;br&gt;
(grace and peace)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;- Carson&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example preprint / working paper</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/publication/preprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/publication/preprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-wowchemy&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Wowchemy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/slides/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/pdf-export/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Eating...&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  Three
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Only the speaker can read these notes
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Press &lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;`S`&lt;/span&gt; key to view
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  {{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/media/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;/media/boards.jpg&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;#0000FF&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;my-style&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34; data-lang=&#34;css&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;navy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/slides/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Project</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/project/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/project/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Duis posuere tellus ac convallis placerat. Proin tincidunt magna sed ex sollicitudin condimentum. Sed ac faucibus dolor, scelerisque sollicitudin nisi. Cras purus urna, suscipit quis sapien eu, pulvinar tempor diam. Quisque risus orci, mollis id ante sit amet, gravida egestas nisl. Sed ac tempus magna. Proin in dui enim. Donec condimentum, sem id dapibus fringilla, tellus enim condimentum arcu, nec volutpat est felis vel metus. Vestibulum sit amet erat at nulla eleifend gravida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nullam vel molestie justo. Curabitur vitae efficitur leo. In hac habitasse platea dictumst. Sed pulvinar mauris dui, eget varius purus congue ac. Nulla euismod, lorem vel elementum dapibus, nunc justo porta mi, sed tempus est est vel tellus. Nam et enim eleifend, laoreet sem sit amet, elementum sem. Morbi ut leo congue, maximus velit ut, finibus arcu. In et libero cursus, rutrum risus non, molestie leo. Nullam congue quam et volutpat malesuada. Sed risus tortor, pulvinar et dictum nec, sodales non mi. Phasellus lacinia commodo laoreet. Nam mollis, erat in feugiat consectetur, purus eros egestas tellus, in auctor urna odio at nibh. Mauris imperdiet nisi ac magna convallis, at rhoncus ligula cursus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cras aliquam rhoncus ipsum, in hendrerit nunc mattis vitae. Duis vitae efficitur metus, ac tempus leo. Cras nec fringilla lacus. Quisque sit amet risus at ipsum pharetra commodo. Sed aliquam mauris at consequat eleifend. Praesent porta, augue sed viverra bibendum, neque ante euismod ante, in vehicula justo lorem ac eros. Suspendisse augue libero, venenatis eget tincidunt ut, malesuada at lorem. Donec vitae bibendum arcu. Aenean maximus nulla non pretium iaculis. Quisque imperdiet, nulla in pulvinar aliquet, velit quam ultrices quam, sit amet fringilla leo sem vel nunc. Mauris in lacinia lacus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse a tincidunt lacus. Curabitur at urna sagittis, dictum ante sit amet, euismod magna. Sed rutrum massa id tortor commodo, vitae elementum turpis tempus. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Aenean purus turpis, venenatis a ullamcorper nec, tincidunt et massa. Integer posuere quam rutrum arcu vehicula imperdiet. Mauris ullamcorper quam vitae purus congue, quis euismod magna eleifend. Vestibulum semper vel augue eget tincidunt. Fusce eget justo sodales, dapibus odio eu, ultrices lorem. Duis condimentum lorem id eros commodo, in facilisis mauris scelerisque. Morbi sed auctor leo. Nullam volutpat a lacus quis pharetra. Nulla congue rutrum magna a ornare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aliquam in turpis accumsan, malesuada nibh ut, hendrerit justo. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Quisque sed erat nec justo posuere suscipit. Donec ut efficitur arcu, in malesuada neque. Nunc dignissim nisl massa, id vulputate nunc pretium nec. Quisque eget urna in risus suscipit ultricies. Pellentesque odio odio, tincidunt in eleifend sed, posuere a diam. Nam gravida nisl convallis semper elementum. Morbi vitae felis faucibus, vulputate orci placerat, aliquet nisi. Aliquam erat volutpat. Maecenas sagittis pulvinar purus, sed porta quam laoreet at.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Project</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/project/external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/project/external-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example journal article</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/publication/journal-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/publication/journal-article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example conference paper</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/publication/conference-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/publication/conference-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
