<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog | Carson Slater&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://carsonslater.com/category/blog/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://carsonslater.com/category/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blog</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://carsonslater.com/media/icon_hu157031afba4586da11a934f6f1896e51_654558_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/category/blog/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my blog!</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-even-is-this&#34;&gt;What even is this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a place where I plan on sharing my thoughts, experienes, and things I have found to be encouragements in my life!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why&lt;/strong&gt;: This blog is inspired by my desire to encourage people to follow Jesus. More specifically, I was inspired by a practice my church group did when we were serving in the Czech Republic through an organization called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.josiahventure.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Josiah Venture&lt;/a&gt;, where we &lt;a href=&#34;https://fbcaz.com/all-good/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;blogged&lt;/a&gt; about our experiences to bring our local church body alongside us our Journey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To Whom&lt;/strong&gt;: The intended audience for this blog is anyone who is partnering with me in my endeavors to share the gospel with youth. While my intended audience is limited, this blog is actually for anyone and everyone! Please join in praying for me as I prepare to spend my summer as an intern with Josiah Venture!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-you-plan-on-posting-here&#34;&gt;What do you plan on posting here?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to share with you my experiences preparing for my JV summer internship, as well as my experiences during the internship. After my time in Czechía, I will be able to reflect on the things that God was showing me along the way!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I also have ambitions to publish some of my own writing here - mainly about books I want to review, ideas I want to share, and things I would love to invite you to consider!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-josiahventurehttpswwwjosiahventurecom&#34;&gt;What is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.josiahventure.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JosiahVenture&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josiah Venture is a para-church missions organization focused on raising up youth leaders in Central and Eastern Europe. There mission statement can be found on their website, but I&amp;rsquo;ve retrieved it here for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&#34;This is the vision of Josiah Venture, a vision for a movement of God among the youth of Central and Eastern Europe that finds its home in the local church and transforms society. Our mission and calling is to equip young leaders to fulfill Christ’s commission by reaching and making disciples. More than just conversion, we want to see passionate followers of Jesus Christ, with a vision to reach and disciple their generation for him.&#34;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heartbeat behind Josiah Venture is actually based off the story of King Josiah of Israel&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
