<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog | Carson Slater&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://carsonslater.com/tag/blog/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://carsonslater.com/tag/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blog</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://carsonslater.com/media/icon_hu157031afba4586da11a934f6f1896e51_654558_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/tag/blog/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Biblical Theology of Mission?</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/post/bibtheomissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/post/bibtheomissions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-write-this&#34;&gt;Why Write This?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greetings! As I am spending my summer doing missions in Europe, and I wanted to dig a little bit deeper into how missions fits into God&amp;rsquo;s overarching plan to redeem humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would love to point out that although this article has everything to do with what I am doing this summer, it simultaneously has nothing to do with the specific particularities of my summer. My reflections on mission are simply an exercise of preparation as I gear up for the coming season. Hence, this post most definitely will feel a little more dry if you are expecting something personal. I hope you find that reflecting on God&amp;rsquo;s holistic plan introduces a new, vibrant lens that showcases the significance of our day to day ministry tasks we engage in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-point&#34;&gt;The Point&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing theology for the sake of the intellectual stimulation, or knowledge acquisition, can be profitable and well intented; however, the reason I write this article is to invite people to &lt;em&gt;know God&lt;/em&gt;. Knowing God is infinitely more valuable than having wrestled with all theological topics and concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theology is an  opportunity to better understand and seek God for the sake of intimacy. My prayer for this article is that if you read this, you may be introduced to a new or better understanding of the epic plan for God&amp;rsquo;s people, and maybe catch a new glimpse of the Planner Himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-biblical-theology&#34;&gt;What is Biblical Theology?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I had heard the phrase, &amp;lsquo;Biblical Theology&amp;rsquo; in a Christian circle. Naively, my knee jerk reaction was: &amp;ldquo;Isn&amp;rsquo;t all Theology Biblical?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
It turns out that I was wrong, at least in one sense. What I ended up learning is that there are different ways of doing theology. There are different approaches that can be taken to learning about God. To quote Andrew David Naselli,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Biblical theology is a way of analyzing and synthesizing the Bible that makes organic, salvation-historical connections with the whole canon on its own terms, especially how the Old and New Testaments progress, integrate, and climax in Christ.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a shortcut, the framework I like to use to think about biblical theology is by comparing it to other ways of doing theology. At its core, biblical theology, systematic theology, and historical theology are all avenues of studying God, but they are distinct in their own right. Historical theology is beautiful because it heavily considers and analyzes church history and theological development. Systematic theology presupposes questions and goes to Scriputre for answers, for the sake of building a robust framework to think about God. Biblical Theology, on the other hand, is exegesis in light of the whole Scripture. Biblical Theology uses the historical narrative of the Bible, and allows Scripture to raise questions about God on its own terms. It consults the development of the redemptive narrative for answers, and engages typologies to trace big thematic elements in the Bible. This is why Biblical Theology is of particular interest to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-biblical-theology-of-mission&#34;&gt;A Biblical Theology of Mission&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-few-disclaimers&#34;&gt;A Few Disclaimers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to put my cards on the table by acknowledging that I am by no means a theological scholar, rather I am just a humble college student. I may grow excited in my writing about specific salvation-historical connections, but at the end of the day, there are some sobering facts to acknowledge about the mission of the people of God:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is sovereign. (Ps. 115:3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humanity cannot save themselves. (Eph. 2:1-3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God invites humanity into reconciliation, not only restoring humanity to a relationship with Himself, but inviting us to become co-laborers with Him. (2 Cor. 5:17-19)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The entirety of the people of God will be able to worship God in unity with Christ, resulting in passionate praise for all eternity. (Rev. 5:9-10)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God invites His people to participate in this outpouring of salvation by enabling them to become lights in a dark world; the people of God are not the source of the light, but the conduit. (2 Cor. 4:5-7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more disclaimer is that the discipline of Biblical Theology is like a game of pick-up-sticks. It is hard to trace one particular theme without disturbing or untangling it from other themes in Scripture, as they are heavily interwoven. Hence, in this article I may gloss over really important facts that are relevant but mostly relate to over themes in Scripture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-original-comission&#34;&gt;The Original Comission&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When God created the earth, He created His image within a garden sanctuary. It was the place where the people had &lt;em&gt;intimate communion with God&lt;/em&gt;. Afterwards, humanity reject this calling by imitating the serpent. Ultimately, God still wanted to magnify Himself in the universe, with the people that He had originally created. After cursing the earth, God still promised to deliver His people from their rebellion, restoring them to be right-working image-bearers of Himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-blessing-for-all-nations&#34;&gt;A Blessing for All Nations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get a glimpse for God&amp;rsquo;s plan to reconcile all peoples to Himself when He commissions Abram to go forth to possess a specific portion of Canaan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Now the Lord said to Abram, “Go forth from your country, And from your relatives And from your father’s house, To the land which I will show you; And I will make you a great nation, And I will bless you, And make your name great; And so you shall be a blessing; And I will bless those who bless you, And the one who curses you I will curse. And in you all the families of the earth will be blessed.&amp;quot;&amp;rsquo; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people are quick to point out how in Abram &amp;ldquo;all the families of the earth will be blessed.&amp;rdquo; What tends to be overlooked is that God states that Abram is to be a blessing &lt;strong&gt;in the land to which He is going&lt;/strong&gt;. Dr. Jason S. DeRouchie notes that God&amp;rsquo;s covenant with Abram required that He go to Canaan, so that He may become a great nation (Israel), but that eventually one day Abram (or perhaps His representative) would be a blessing to all nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;come-and-see&#34;&gt;Come and See&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abram then became Abraham, and His offspring endured 400+ years of slavery in Egypt. Following the Exodus, God used this offspring (again, the nation Israel) to mediate God&amp;rsquo;s presence and blessings to the surrounding nations. Through radical submission, Abraham&amp;rsquo;s offspring would serve as holy representatives to a needy world. Israel as a nation was not evangelistic; their mission was to cultivate a covenant community that was not exclusive to foreigners. Hence, Israel&amp;rsquo;s culture, customs and laws served as an invitation to the world to &amp;lsquo;come and see&amp;rsquo; what God was doing. This was Israel&amp;rsquo;s &amp;rsquo;limited&amp;rsquo; mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;visions-of-hope-and-reconciliation&#34;&gt;Visions of Hope and Reconciliation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people of God now are living in covenant community in the land, and prophecies begin to emerge and reminding Israel that God&amp;rsquo;s promises were to bring good news for all nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the Lord all the offspring of Israel will be justified and will glory.” &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blessing is depicted in Isaiah by the servant songs. These songs depict a &amp;lsquo;servant&amp;rsquo; that ministers to both Israel and the nations. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This royal servant would&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enjoy God&amp;rsquo;s presence and would fulfill his mission to bring justice to the nations, (&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/100/ISA.42.1-4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Isa. 42:1-4&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;engage in a ministry of mercy, (&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/100/ISA.51.4-5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Isa. 51:4-5&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;guide the lost, (&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/100/ISA.61.1-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Isa. 61:1-3&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serve as a covenant mediator,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;open the eyes of the blind and deliver the captive, (&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/100/ISA.42.6-7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Isa.42:6-7&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and preach the good news of God&amp;rsquo;s victory over evil and God&amp;rsquo;s saving grace. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/100/ISA.52.7-10&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Isa. 52:7-10&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/100/ISA.61.1-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; 61:1-3&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only in Isaiah do we see God&amp;rsquo;s heart for the nations, but also in Jonah. Many like to pigeonhole Jonah as the missionary archetype, but I would particularly argue that He was appointed for a specific mission rather than as a New Covenant missionary. Jonah serves as an example of &lt;em&gt;Israel&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; outreach to the nations, but is helpful to acknowledge in a Biblical Theology of mission because he serves as a reminder that God is always interested in the whole world. This is all despite His choosing of Israel to mediate for Him initially within the salvation-historical narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-new-covenant-in-christ&#34;&gt;The New Covenant in Christ&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we find is that Jesus arrives as the incarnate God, and He fulfills these prophecies of the servant in Isaiah. Not only does He accomplish this, but He fulfills the Law, conquers death, and institutes the New Covenant.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In this New Covenant, the people of God take on posture of faith, which leads to obedience and extends worship beyond the walls of the temple. The people of God are no longer exclusively Jews, but also Gentiles, making salvation available for all peoples of all nations.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;go-and-tell&#34;&gt;Go and Tell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Jesus&amp;rsquo;s last statements before the ascension was the Great Commission. Before sending His disciples - the people of God - out into the world to teach all that He had taught, He reminds His disciples that &amp;ldquo;all authority on heaven and earth has been given to&amp;rdquo; Himself.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Christians on mission do well to observe the omnipotence and authority of their Master, their Savior Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This commission amends to the overall disposition of the people of God as a &amp;lsquo;come and see&amp;rsquo; covenant community to also a &amp;lsquo;go and tell&amp;rsquo; mindset. In the Old Testament, God&amp;rsquo;s people are a kingdom of priests and a holy nation. Now the church, filled and empowered by the Holy Spirit, also acts as God&amp;rsquo;s dynamic living temple-sanctuary who aims to shine lights in a dark world. The church was created to show the rest of the world who their beautiful Creator and Sustainer is. The church truly is the fulfillment of Acts 1:8, where Jesus before His ascension states that His disciples will receive the outpouring of the Holy Spirit, and go to the ends of the earth to bear witness and testimony about the Lord. &lt;em&gt;The church was made for mission.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-his-kingdom-comes&#34;&gt;When His Kingdom Comes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salvation truly does belong to the Lamb who sits on the throne.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; One of the most beautiful passages of Scripture is in Revelation 5:9. Here John the apostle describes a vision where people from every nation, tribe, and tongue are worshiping God. As John Piper once wrote, &amp;lsquo;Missions exists because worship doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&amp;rsquo; One reason the kingdom of God possesses beauty is because it is multi-ethnic! God has invited His people, the church, into this mission of self-revelation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As God&amp;rsquo;s image bearers rejected their duties to bear God&amp;rsquo;s image, God enacted a plan to magnify Himself in the universe. Seeking reconciliation with all peoples, God promised that the seed of the woman would crush the head of the serpent, whom the people imitated. He promised to bless all the nations of the earth through the line of Abram, and build up a covenant nation called to be set apart for God&amp;rsquo;s purposes. This community was to be a nation of holy priests so that all other nations might &amp;lsquo;come and see&amp;rsquo; what God was doing in Israel. After continual promises of restoration, God sent the Messiah as He promised. This suffering servant instituted the New Covenant, adding a &amp;lsquo;go and tell&amp;rsquo; posture to the people of God, outpouring His power onto them through the Holy Spirit, all so that the world may worship Him one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;application&#34;&gt;Application&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking holistically about mission through a biblical theological framework must not be mistaken for a thought experiment! Biblical Theology is a tool that can prevent Christians from missing the forest for the trees. Not only does this help us observe God&amp;rsquo;s overarching plan for His people, but it uncovers His heart for humanity. Additionally, seeing the entirety of God&amp;rsquo;s plan for His people serves as a humbling reminder for how small, yet crucial of a role each individual plays in the plan. In the midst of the knitty-gritty details of our respective ministries, such as serving at an English Camp in Europe, we can be reminded that nothing can stand in the way of God as He accomplishes His plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/40-Questions-About-Biblical-Theology/dp/0825445604/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=40&amp;#43;questions&amp;#43;about&amp;#43;biblical&amp;#43;theology&amp;amp;qid=1678473716&amp;amp;sprefix=40&amp;#43;questions&amp;#43;about&amp;#43;bibl%2Caps%2C124&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;40 Questions About Biblical Theology, Chapter 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/100/GEN.12.1-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Genesis 12:1-3&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.bible.com/bible/100/ISA.45.25&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Isaiah 45:25&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Isaiah 42:1–4; Isaiah 49:1–6; Isaiah 50:4–11; and Isaiah 52:13–53:12&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Mark 1:14-15, Luke 22:14-20&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Isaiah 11:10, Galatians 3:8, 14, 16, 29&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Matthew 28:19-20&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Revelation 7:9-10&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Heartbeat Behind Support Raising</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/post/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/post/support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I prepare for the upcoming summer, I have been tasked with raising $5400 of support by May 1; that gives me just over a month to raise the funds from the time of posting this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-temptation&#34;&gt;The Temptation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I confess that as someone who is supposed to be paying attention to the quantity of funding coming in, it is very easy to uphold a reductionist attitude toward support raising. It can easily be boiled down to be a means to an end. This is such a counter-intuitive way to think about it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I neglect the people on the other side of my invitation for support, I miss out on so many things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Whoever brings blessing will be enriched, and one who waters will himself be watered.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;partnership&#34;&gt;Partnership&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at one of the first-ever New Covenant short-term missionaries in Scripture. His name was Epaphroditus, and a short blurb was written about him in Philippians 2:25-30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Paul, Epaphroditus was sent to him in Rome by the church of Philippi, and he was able to deliver necessary supplies to Paul to assist with his ministry. Although it does not specify how, Epaphroditus nearly dies of illness while on this journey. I want to highlight what Paul says about him though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have thought it necessary to send to you Epaphroditus my brother and fellow soldier, and your messenger and minister to my need.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epaphroditus was used as the tangible component of the church of Philippi&amp;rsquo;s partnership with Paul. Recall that in chapter 1 of Philippians,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Paul writes about his partnership with the church of Philippi. Here are some of the things he writes about them as his supporters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every time he thinks of them, he thanks God. (v. 3-4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He considers them partners in the gospel. (v. 5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He reminds the church of the perfect work of Jesus in them being brought to completion via sanctification. (v. 6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He considers them partakers of grace. (v. 7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hope and prayer is that if you choose to partner with me in prayer or with financial support, please let me know and reach out! I would love to pray for you as you partake in the grace that God has bestowed upon you and others in your proximity. We can partner together to make known the riches of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s kindness. I certainly have been forgiven much, so it only makes sense that I love others much by sharing a salvific message with them, to the glory of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reducing the supporter-supportee relationship to a transaction yields minimal fruit, if any. There are so many blessings that come from that rich fellowship, and the Paul-Philippi example is no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-invitation-to-co-labor&#34;&gt;An Invitation to Co-Labor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heartbeat behind support raising is to invite people into ministry through prayer and financial support. I hope to engage in mutual encouragement and prayer to labor and yearn for the kingdom of God on this earth &lt;strong&gt;together&lt;/strong&gt;, and the for redemption of the lost. I pray that reports of my efforts would elicit or inspire a Spirit-driven desire within you to engage in gospel work where you are at. Thank you to everyone who has set such a phenomenal example for me in my upbringing of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bold-faith&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BOLD&lt;/strong&gt; Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that if God is bigger than all I can ask or imagine, and that if He calls me His son, He would have no problem with me asking for great things in &lt;strong&gt;bold faith&lt;/strong&gt;. God is investing in His children to yield a return of 30, 60, or 100 fold! Investors want their investments to yield 100-fold returns! That is exactly why I am inviting everyone I can into this partnership, asking for as much as they are able to give cheerfully. I am so excited to see what God does this summer when He chooses to move in the regions of central and eastern Europe. I truly hold onto this exhoration in 2 Corinthians:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;&amp;ldquo;And God is able to make all grace abound to you, so that having all sufficiency in all things at all times, you may abound in every good work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nice-theory-but-what-about-practice&#34;&gt;Nice Theory, but What About Practice?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How will I invite you into this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already received one, I&amp;rsquo;d love to send you a support letter! It gives details of my trip, what I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing, and what to pray for as I prepare for my summer missionary internship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, if you feel led, I invite you to give! You can click &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.josiahventure.com/give-form/?designation=689836c4-8b96-407c-afb1-27c679d96029&amp;amp;user=53992&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to find the online donation portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would be remissed if our contact stopped at those two pathways. I encourage you to go to the home page and fill out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://carsonslater.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt; with a message desribing how I can stay in contact with you. I can also add you to the subscriber list for when I post for this blog! This blog will be updated weekly while I am in Europe, so stay tuned for prayer requests!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, my phone number is on the contact page as well. I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you with any prayer requests you have that I can be praying for. This will help me be aware of what God is doing in your life, and how I can encourage you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My cell phone number is +1 (480) 320-8898. Text me anytime!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-am-fighting-for-this-posture&#34;&gt;How I am Fighting for This Posture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josiah Venture actually had me take a small reflective course on support raising. Support raising can be uncomfortable because you don&amp;rsquo;t see the other side of what you believe God is calling you into, until you get there. In other words, I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I will have all of my funds raised by May 1, but I know that God can provide. This is an opportunity to trust in His provision, even though I cannot see the outcome. This is inherently uncomfortable, but that is okay! In my support raising course, I was asked to chart out a few lies I was fighting to reject. I was then asked to rebuke those same lies with the truth. Here are some of the things I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lie 1&lt;/strong&gt;: I can control the things that truly aren&amp;rsquo;t within my control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Truth 1&lt;/strong&gt;: At the end of the day, I do not control how many people decide to support me, but I can be faithful by inviting them into this process and journey with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lie 2&lt;/strong&gt;: I can passively wait for God to provide support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Truth 2&lt;/strong&gt;: Faithfulness is an active posture. I still need to invite support from others, and trust God will take care of the rest. Money or prayer from others does not &amp;lsquo;fall out of the sky&amp;rsquo; in this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lie 3&lt;/strong&gt;: My prayers do not do anything in the support raising process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Truth 3&lt;/strong&gt;: Prayer is not preparation for the work. Prayer IS the work. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; God invites us to petition for His provision as an act of faith and worship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-expression-of-gratitude&#34;&gt;An Expression of Gratitude&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ι hope this post is able to unpack the nuance surrounding my support raising journey for you. I pray that as you consider joining what God is doing in Central and Eastern Europe, that God will begin to unveil things in your own heart, that you yourself may grow in intimacy with Him. He is the true fount of our salvation; He is our portion! Thanks be to God, for enabling us to co-labor with Him as broken yet mighty vessels of grace, by the power of His Holy Spirit. Thank you for taking the time to read this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
χάριτος καἰ εἰρήνη,&lt;br&gt;
(grace and peace)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;- Carson&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proverbs 11:25 &lt;em&gt;ESV&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philippians 2:25 &lt;em&gt;ESV&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philippians 1:3-7 &lt;em&gt;ESV&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians 9:8 &lt;em&gt;ESV&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oswald Chambers, &lt;em&gt;My Utmost for His Highest&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returning to Europe</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/post/returning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/post/returning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear reader,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that if you take the time to read this post, you may be encouraged to draw near to Jesus Christ, through whom are all things and to whom are all things. My prayer is that you grow in the assurance of your calling to reconciliation with God and His mission on this earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-prior-experiences&#34;&gt;My Prior Experiences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last summer, I had the amazing opportunity to join a team from my church in Arizona on a trip to the Czech Republic where we partnered with a local Czech church to facilitate an English Camp. At this camp, we shared the gospel with youth in their area through various talks and small group discussions in the evenings. I embarked on the trip with an awareness of Europe’s larger attitude toward Protestant Christianity, having previously served in Romania three times, but I came back to the States with a yearning to return, in order that I may continue to walk in the good works the Lord has prepared for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am excited to write to you now to inform you that God has provided an opportunity for me to return to the Czech Republic, only for a longer period of time. After going to Europe to engage people with the gospel four times, I cannot deny the strategy I see behind living in Europe as a Christian, let alone serving alongside missionaries who are already actively working there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-why&#34;&gt;My &amp;lsquo;Why&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I currently attend college in a city that is ranked on this list for the most churches per capita in the world. I grew up less than a mile away from two large churches, and even a Presbyterian church to sweeten the deal. My experiences in Europe have shown me that a European mega-church usually consists of around 100 members, as opposed to the 2,000+ members that I am prone to visualize when I picture a stereotypical American mega-church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mention this to illustrate that in America, people actually have options of where they choose to go to church, which is not a reality everywhere in Europe. This disparity points to the notion that there is much work to be done in exposing people to the gospel in Europe. There are so many people in Europe living a life that has never been exposed to Jesus in a personal way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The population of the Czech Republic is approximately 0.737% evangelical &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s right. Less than a percent. However, this percent has a growth rate of 0.3% per year! There are believers on the ground in this nation, and I am honored to be given the opportunity to walk alongside them for two and a half months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-posture&#34;&gt;My Posture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last summer, I was able to serve at English Camp with a Church in Český Těšín, CZ. I was coming out of a very heavy season of life, where I had just quit baseball (I had played for 13 years and gotten to the college level) and was convicted that I had used it as an means to glorify myself. I had been drawn to missions in high school before, but after coming to Wheaton, I was less mindful of it while pursuing other passions that I have since deemed as not conducive to spiritual growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was in this heavy season, one of my pastors at my church in Wheaton shared a verse with me before I left for Europe last summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For we are His workmanship, created in Christ Jesus for good works, which God prepared beforehand so that we would walk in them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
(Ephesians 2:10 NASB)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I was encouraged when I heard it, I had no clue how clear this would become while I was serving. I was able to reframe missions as my participation in building the most honorable kingdom - the kingdom of God. Missions was not the passion of my past, rather it was restored as a means by which I could walk in the good works God has prepared for me. I want to accept this invitation from the Lord to partake in His masterful building plan for His kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By no means am I saying that missions is the ONLY way to walk in the good works God has prepared for me. That would be to suppose the sacred-secular divide is real, which is not true. I just know that the Holy Spirit empowered me to get excited about sharing my first love with other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, I am going back. I am by no means sufficient to carry this out on my own, but I know God&amp;rsquo;s power is perfected in my weakness. I just need to act in faith and obedience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
χάριτος καἰ εἰρήνη,&lt;br&gt;
(grace and peace)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;- Carson&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. If you want to inquire or chat, please feel free to reach out on the contact form of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://carsonslater.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;home page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://globe.stratus.earth/country-explorer/CZE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Joshua Project via Stratus Earth&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my blog!</title>
      <link>https://carsonslater.com/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carsonslater.com/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-even-is-this&#34;&gt;What even is this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a place where I plan on sharing my thoughts, experienes, and things I have found to be encouragements in my life!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why&lt;/strong&gt;: This blog is inspired by my desire to encourage people to follow Jesus. More specifically, I was inspired by a practice my church group did when we were serving in the Czech Republic through an organization called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.josiahventure.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Josiah Venture&lt;/a&gt;, where we &lt;a href=&#34;https://fbcaz.com/all-good/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;blogged&lt;/a&gt; about our experiences to bring our local church body alongside us our Journey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To Whom&lt;/strong&gt;: The intended audience for this blog is anyone who is partnering with me in my endeavors to share the gospel with youth. While my intended audience is limited, this blog is actually for anyone and everyone! Please join in praying for me as I prepare to spend my summer as an intern with Josiah Venture!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-you-plan-on-posting-here&#34;&gt;What do you plan on posting here?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to share with you my experiences preparing for my JV summer internship, as well as my experiences during the internship. After my time in Czechía, I will be able to reflect on the things that God was showing me along the way!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I also have ambitions to publish some of my own writing here - mainly about books I want to review, ideas I want to share, and things I would love to invite you to consider!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-josiahventurehttpswwwjosiahventurecom&#34;&gt;What is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.josiahventure.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JosiahVenture&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josiah Venture is a para-church missions organization focused on raising up youth leaders in Central and Eastern Europe. Their mission statement can be found on their website, but I&amp;rsquo;ve retrieved it here for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&#34;This is the vision of Josiah Venture, a vision for a movement of God among the youth of Central and Eastern Europe that finds its home in the local church and transforms society. Our mission and calling is to equip young leaders to fulfill Christ’s commission by reaching and making disciples. More than just conversion, we want to see passionate followers of Jesus Christ, with a vision to reach and disciple their generation for him.&#34;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heartbeat behind Josiah Venture is actually derived from the story of King Josiah of Israel (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bible.com/bible/59/2CH.34.ESV&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;read here&lt;/a&gt;). He inherits the throne of Israel at age eight. He did what was right in the eyes of God, purged the nation of places reserved for idol worship, and sought to reorient the people to follow God once again. As an organization, Josiah Venture seeks to find and raise up more Josiah&amp;rsquo;s across Central and Eastern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-will-you-be-serving&#34;&gt;How will you be serving?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be serving alongside the current Josiah Venture missionaries that are already in Czechía by partnering with local churches to promote, plan, and facilitate English Camps across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-you-give-me-a-preview-of-what-this-will-look-like-somehow&#34;&gt;Can you give me a preview of what this will look like somehow?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t exactly look into the future, but I imagine it will look similar to the camp I served last summer, when my church in AZ partnered with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cbtesin.cz/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;local Czech church&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/h3TBU2FuNTE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope I anticipated the questions you might have. If not, feel free to contact me with more questions via the form on the home page. I was led to create this blog in December 2022, and it is super fun to finally see it come to fruition. Glory be to God, and may this page be one that is edifying to all who read it!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
My hope and prayer is that if you have chosen to let Jesus rule over your life, that you may be spurred on to love and good works (Hebrews 10:24), and that if you do not yet have Jesus as the ruler of your life, that you’d stick around for the sake of curiosity. After all, I’ll probably be posting more than just summer preparatory items on here! &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
χάριτος καἰ εἰρήνη,&lt;br&gt;
(grace and peace)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;- Carson&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
